<?xml version="1.0"?>
<book xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation='http://www.docbook.org/xsd/4.4/docbook.xsd' >
<!-- :indentSize=2:tabSize=2:noTabs=true: -->
<bookinfo>
  <title>Patchfile SideKick Plugin Guide</title>
  <authorgroup>
    <author><firstname>Marc</firstname><surname>Häfner</surname></author>
  </authorgroup>

  <legalnotice>
    <title>Legal Notice</title>
    <para>
      Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document
      under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.1 or
      any later version published by the Free Software Foundation; with no
      <quote>Invariant Sections</quote>, <quote>Front-Cover Texts</quote> or
      <quote>Back-Cover Texts</quote>, each as defined in the license. A copy
      of the license can be found in the file
      <filename>COPYING.DOC.txt</filename> included with jEdit.
    </para>
  </legalnotice>
</bookinfo>

<chapter id="intro"><title>Introduction</title>
  <para>
    This plugin provides a simple parser for diff files (aka patch files) in
    unified and context format. It shows the paths of diffed files in the
    structure tree.
  </para>
</chapter>

<chapter id="display"><title>The structure tree</title>
  <para>
    The structure tree shows the full file paths in the same order as they
    appear in the diff file.
  </para>
  <para>
    If changes range over two files, both files will be shown with a
    <code>&gt;</code> between them. If the new file is in the same directory
    as the original, only its filename will be displayed.
  </para>
  <para>
    Created or deleted files will be prepended with <code>+</code> and
    <code>-</code> respectively.
  </para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <para>
      Git diff format extensions are recognized (in unified diff format):
    </para>
    <listitem><para>
      Path prefixes <code>a/</code> and <code>b/</code> will be removed from
      original and new file.
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
      A path <code>/dev/null</code> will be interpreted as indicating file
      creation or deletion.
    </para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</chapter>

<chapter id="limitations"><title>Limitations</title>
  <itemizedlist>
    <para>
      This very simple parser is written for real-world diff files and does
      not handle possible but unusual situations:
    </para>
    <listitem><para>
      Path separators are expected to be POSIX-style forward slashes
      ("<code>/</code>").
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
      The first header line must contain the original file. The new file must
      be on the next line.
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
      A file path on a preceding <code>Index:</code> line is not used if no
      other path information is available. (As opposed to the patch tool).
    </para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>
      The parser does not check if a file is actually a git diff. This may
      have unexpected side effects if directories are named <code>a</code> and
      <code>b</code>.
    </para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</chapter>

<chapter id="license"><title>License and Acknowledgments</title>
  <para>
    Released under the <ulink url="http://opensource.org/licenses/MIT">MIT
    License.</ulink>
  </para>
</chapter>
</book>
